Jewett mss., 1914-1929 LMC 3007
Lilly Library
Jewett mss.
1914-1929
Lilly Library
Jewett, Charles Webster, 1884-1961
LMC 3007
2 Boxes
The Jewett mss., 1914-1929, consists of scrapbooks, chiefly of news clippings, about and relating to Indianapolis lawyer and politician Charles Webster Jewett, 1884-1961.
Access Restrictions
This collection is open for research.
Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please make an appointment a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.
Acquisition Information
Acquired: 2007
Biographical Note
Charles Webster Jewett, 1884-1961, was an Indiana lawyer and politician. He was born on January 7, 1884 in Franklin, Indiana. He first attended DePauw University from 1903 to 1907, then studied law at Harvard University, graduating in 1910. On October 25, 1911 he married Elizabeth Dougherty Jewett. He was chosen as the chairman of the Marion County Republican Committee in 1914 and would go on to be the Republican candidate for Governor of Indiana in 1928. He would also run an unsuccessful bid for a seat in the House of Representatives in 1938. He is best known for serving as the mayor of Indianapolis from 1918 to 1921. He died in Indianapolis April 28, 1961 and is interred in that city's Crown Hill Cemetery.
Scope and Content Note
The Jewett mss., 1914-1929, consist of scrapbooks, chiefly of news clippings, about and relating to Indianapolis lawyer and politician Charles Webster Jewett, 1884-1961. Most of the clippings deal with his political career, his mayoral years, and his Republican party activities up to and including his campaign for Governor.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged following original order.
Mayors --Indiana --Indianapolis.; Politicians --Indiana --Biography.; Scrapbooks --Specimens.; Indiana--Politics and government; Jewett, Charles Webster, 1844-1961.; Republican party (Ind.)
- Collection (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Contains seven volumes with the following date spans:
  - Sept. 1914 - Dec. 1917 (Box 1)
  - Sept. - Nov. 1914 (Box 1)
  - Dec. 1915 - Nov. 1916 (Box 1)
  - Nov. 1916 - Sept. 1917 (Box 1)
  - Nov. 1916 - Nov. 1917 (Box 1)
  - Sept. - Oct. 1917 (Box 1)
  - 1918 - 1919 (Box 1)
  - 1918-1919 (Box 2)
  - 1919 - 1921, (2 volumes) (Box 2)
  - Apr. 1927 - 1929 (Box 2)
  - Apr. - May 1928 (Box 2)